《寂静岭2：启示》
你打不赢我的
You cannot defeat me.
不要去寂静岭
Do not go to Silent Hill.
宝贝 没事了
Honey, it's okay.
有我在呢…
I'm here…
嗯
Yes?
- 火在烧我… - 没事的 孩子 一个噩梦而已
- I was burning… - Hey come on, kiddo, it was just a dream.
每次搬家后你都会做噩梦
Just like this morning…
- 这次感觉不一样 - 听我说…
- This feels different… - Hey look…
我们来把东西规整好 把房子粉刷一下
Once we've unpacked and give this place a lick of paint…
就像自己的家了
This will be our home.
- 噩梦会逐渐消淡 - 他们在叫我
- The dreams will fade. - They're calling me.
别听他们说
Do not listen.
不要听 你听他们的话了？
Do not listen. Do you hear?
答应我 不管如何 不要去那里
I want you to promise me that whatever happens, you'll never go there…
好了
Okay.
又做噩梦了？
Rough night?
嗯
Yeah.
爸爸 我不想再搬家了
Daddy, I don't want to do this again.
知道了 宝贝
I know, honey.
没拿勺…
Spoons…
「茜瑟」 为什么叫茜瑟？
"Heather." Why Heather?
是我奶奶的名字 你要是不喜欢就自己改一个
It was my grandmother's name.
不用了
No, no.
叫茜瑟挺好的
Heather is fine.
我叫过莎伦 玛丽 然后叫凯西 现在叫茜瑟
I was Sharon, then Mary, then Cathy. Now Heather.
你原来叫克里斯多佛 现在叫哈利
And you were Christopher and now you're Harry.
名字又没多大用
Names don't matter.
我还是我
I'm still me.
生日快乐！
Happy birthday!
老爸 谢谢你！但是你送早了吧
Dad, thank you! But you're, you're early.
是有点早
Just a little.
真高兴 我女儿马上都要成年了
Can't believe that today I have a soon-to-be 18 year-old daughter.
- 怎么了？- 没事
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
挺喜欢的
I love it.
- 真的？- 嗯
- Really? - Yes
这就是你在商场盯着看的那件
It is the one I saw you're looking at in the mall.
对 谢谢 我喜欢这件
Yes, yes. Thank you. I love it.
不用谢 宝贝
You're welcome, honey.
你这的头发都白了 老爸
You're getting all that gray there, dad.
都是你的错
Hmmm, your fault.
- 你看 你染得颜色都掉了 - 知道了 我去弄一下
- You know, yours are showing. - Yeah, I know. I'll fix it.
我觉得咱们在这地方挺好的 你觉得呢
I think this place will be good for us, you know? What do you think?
嗯
Yes
开心点 我们规整下东西 把新房子粉刷下怎么样？
Hey, come on. What's say we unpacked, give the new place a lick of paint…
- 我想… - 别 爸爸
- I think… - Don't, Dad.
怎么了？
What?
在我梦里你说了刚才说的话 所以 别说了
It's just what you said in my dream. Just, don't.
我得走了
I got to go.
上学第一天我不想迟到
Do not want to be late on the first day of school.
要记得规矩
Hey, remember the rules.
- 新城市 新学校 - 明白
- New town, new school. - Yes
之前我就这么做的
I've done this before.
我知道 只是有点…
I know you have, I'm just…
- 有点担心 - 别担心
- You know I worry. - Don't worry.
我很小心的 没事的
I'm careful. I'll be fine.
爱你爸爸
I love you.
我也爱你 宝贝
I love you too, honey.
露丝 多希望你还活着
Hey, Rose. I wish you were still here.
从你把莎伦带回来 日子真的很艰辛
It's been so hard since you brought Sharon back to me.
克里斯多佛 我的爱人
Christopher, my love,
露丝
Rose
我一直在找你
I tried to find you
找了很久很久
I searched for so long
我的爱人啊 我的时间不多了
My love, I don't have a lot of time
我被困在这了 你什么都帮不了我
I'm trapped here. There's nothing you can do for me,
保护好女儿
protect her.
- 她现在是最重要的 - 你为什么回不来？
- She's the one that matters now. - Why can't you come back?
我发现了标记 遗失的那部分
I found a Seal. Part of it is missing.
只有我们中的一个可以脱险
Only one of us could come through.
我做了选择
I made a choice.
- 我们的女儿在哪？- 他们会去寻找她的
- Where is our daughter? - They'll come looking for her.
他们会去找她因为他们需要她
They'll come looking because they need her.
别让他们把她带走
Never let them take her.
向我发誓 无论发生什么 无论你做什么
No matter what happens, no matter what you have to do, swear to me.
向我发誓你不会让他们带走她
Swear to me you will never let them take her.
- 我发誓 - 我会把她带回你身边
- I swear. - I brought her back to you.
她现在是你最需关心的人
She is yours to care for now.
别走
Don't go.
再见了 我的爱人
Goodbye, my love.
露丝！
Rose!
爸爸！
Daddy!
莎伦？
Sharon?
哦 我的天 莎伦！
Oh, my God, Sharon!
- 你在这 - 爸爸！
- You are here. - Daddy!
没事了
It's Okay.
现在安全了
You are safe now.
发生了什么事？我什么都不记得了
What happened? I don't remember anything.
没事了 没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
你…
You…
你发生了意外
You were in an accident.
那妈妈呢？
Where's Mommy?
- 是妈妈救了你 - 妈妈呢？
- Mommy saved you. - Where's Mommy?
她走了 宝贝
She's gone, honey.
对不起 我并不是故意想吓你
Sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
- 对不起 说什么？- 你没事吧？
- Sorry, what? - Are you okay?
对 我没事
Yes, I'm fine.
你应该不想被流浪汉骚扰吧
It's just that you don't wanna be messing with the vagrants, miss.
我只是想看看他是不是需要帮助
I just wanted to see if he needed some help.
有些人超出了我们帮助的范围
Some people are beyond our help.
我们见过么？
Have we met?
- 不 不 我想没见过 - 没有？
- No, no, I don't think so. - No?
我很确定见过
I'm sure we have.
- 你叫什么名字？- 我得去赶车了
- What is your name? - I have to catch my bus.
欢迎回来 希望你们过了个愉快的圣诞假期
Welcome back, everyone. I hope you had a good Christmas vacation.
高兴这学期有新同学加入我们班级
I would like to welcome some new students who will be joining us this semester.
茜瑟·曼森 能向大家打声招呼吗？
Heather Mason. Could you say hello to the class, Heather?
大家好 我是茜瑟
Hi. I'm Heather.
刚搬来镇上 所以…
I'm new. I just moved to town, so…
大方点 茜瑟 向大家介绍下自己
Come on, Heather, share a little bit of yourself.
每个人都有故事 和大家说说你的
Everyone has a story. Tell us yours.
这是什么 还是小学三年级吗？
What is this, third grade?
你们想知道什么？
What do you wanna know?
你的衣服都是从旧衣店买的么？
Do you get all of your clothes from goodwill?
好吧 知道吗？
Okay, you know what?
我给你们好好的讲讲吧
Let me make this sincere for you.
这是11岁以来 我换的第5所学校了
This is the fifth school I've been to since I was 11.
我和我爸一直搬家
Me and my dad, we move around.
经历多了 见怪不怪
So I do this, a lot.
所以别想着记住我的名字 因为我很确定我不会记住你们的
So don't bother trying to remember my name because I'm sure as hell not gonna remember yours.
不要和我说话 我们不会成为朋友的
Do not talk to me. We won't be friends.
我不会加你的I.M 或者Facebook Twitter
I won't I.M you or, Facebook you or Tweet you,
浏览你的博客
read your blog.
无论你想说什么 做什么 别麻烦了
And whatever you're thinking of saying or doing, don't bother, because
我见得多了 依我看
I've seen it before, and I'm just guessing here, but…
我并不觉得这屋里有多少有想法的人
I don't think there are too many original thinkers in this room.
当你们有人发现我的一些值得注意的事的时候
And by the time any of you have found
我已经搬走了
I have moved on.
- 行了吧？- 不错
- How's that? - Very impressive.
我们班还有另一位新同学…文森特·库普
Now the next addition to our class, … Vincent Cooper.
你在耍我么？我都不懂你在说什么
Are you kidding me? I can't follow that.
该死！
Shit!
烧死女巫！
Burn the witch!
- 烧死女巫！- 不
- Burn the witch! - No.
- 放开我 - 烧死女巫！
- Please leave me alone. - Burn the Witch!
求你们了！
Please!
放开我…
Leave me alone…
你还好吗？
Are you alright?
- 什么？- 你还好么？
- What? - Are you okay?
你在教室外面干什么？
What are you doing out of class?
我迷路了
You know what? I'm lost.
找不到数学教室了 知道在哪吗？
I can't find Math. Any ideas?
不 不
No, no.
我也找不到路了
I…I'm lost too.
嘿 能一起喝咖啡吗？
Hey look, you wanna get a coffee?
- 不了 我还有课 - 我是说 过会
- No, we have class. - I mean, later.
- 不了 - 为什么？
- No. - Why not?
我们都是新来的 我们都不认识其他人
We're both new. We don't know anyone else.
我在班上讲的那些话 是有原因的
That speech I gave in class, I gave it for a reason.
我确实不想认识这里的任何人
I really do not want to know anyone here.
宝贝 今天怎么样？
Hey, honey. How was your day?
我觉得有人在跟踪我 该怎么办？
I think there's someone following me. What do I do?
好的 啊…
Okay. Uhh…
暂时先别回来 我们在别的地方碰面
Don't come back here. Not yet. I'll meet you somewhere.
中央广场百货
Central Square Mall.
- 你确定下地点 - 好的 在快乐汉堡那见
- You need to make sure. - OK, I'll be the Happy-Hamburg place.
我会尽快到那里
I'll be there as soon as I can.
你觉得有别人知道这事吗？
Do you think someone knows?
没有
No.
没人知道 我尽快去找你
No one knows. I'll see you soon.
- 我爱你 爸爸 - 我也爱你
- I love you, Daddy. - I love you too.
生日快乐 茜瑟！
Happy birthday, Heather!
许个愿吧！
Make a wish!
「生日快乐 茜瑟」
"Happy birthday, HEATHER"
「生日快乐 爱莉」
"Happy birthday, ALESSA"
莎伦
Sharon.
莎伦！
Sharon!
请帮助我 先生…
Please, sir…
莎伦 等等！
Sharon, wait!
爸爸 爸爸…
Daddy, Daddy…
爸爸 我…
Dad, I…
莎伦 等等
Sharon, wait.
莎伦！
Sharon!
离我远点！
Keep away from me!
- 没事的 - 不 怎么没事了
- It's okay. - No, it's not okay.
一切都有事
Nothing is okay.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我叫道格拉斯·卡特兰 我是私家侦探
My name is Douglas Cartland, I'm a private investigator.
你想对我干什么？
What do you want from me?
别人付钱让我找人 有人想找你 莎伦
I'm paid to find people. Someone wanted you found, Sharon.
- 我不叫那名字！- 你是莎伦·达·席尔瓦
- That's not my name! - You're Sharon Da Silva.
至少你是这样叫你自己的 你离开波特兰后我就跟着你
Or at least you think you are. Tracked you down after you left Portland.
你和哈利逃脱了警察 但是我找到你了
You and Harry got away from the police, but I found you.
我父亲的所做所为…只是正当防卫
What my dad did there… That was self-defense.
我不关心哈利杀了谁
I don't care who Harry killed.
- 我是要帮你 - 退后！为什么？
- I'm trying to help. - Get back! Why?
因为我不知道我在为谁工作 但现在知道了
Because I didn't know who I was working for then, but I do now.
他们自称天佑会
They call themselves the Order of Valtiel.
是他们要找你
And they want you.
你骗我
You're lying.
你不明白
You do not understand.
他们知道你在哪
They know where you are.
我告诉了他们你的位置
I told them where you are.
他们要来了 你得逃走
They're coming. You gotta get away.
别担心 我会的
Don't worry, I will.
离我远点！
Keep away from me!
你父亲告诉你的事都不是真的
Everything your dad ever told you was a lie.
去你的！他告诉我的是事实
Fuck you! He told me the truth.
那为什么你都不记得小时候的事？
You know why you don't remember anything from your childhood?
出了车祸 我妈妈死了 我失忆了
I was in a car crash. My mother died. I lost my memory.
错！从来就没有什么车祸
No! There was never any accident.
你被困在一个叫寂静岭的地方
You were trapped in a place called Silent Hill.
但是你母亲救了你 她把你救了出来
But your mother saved you. She got you out.
但是他们想让你回去 问问你爸爸
But they want you back. Ask your dad.
他知道…
He knows that…
告诉我我是谁
Tell me who I am.
不！
No!
求你告诉我
Please tell me.
不！
No!
他走了 他走了
It's gone. It's gone.
我来帮你 快点
I'll help you, come on.
「垃圾」
"Garbage"
你们两个 退后
You two, move back now.
小姐 你不能呆在这
Hey, Miss, you can't be back here.
过来 麻烦到警戒线外面去
Come on, back behind the tape, please.
快点 大家都往后站 大家都退后
Hey come on, folks, I need you back, everybody get back.
等一下
Whoa, whoa, one second.
他的口袋里有一只皮夹
There's a wallet in his pocket.
先生 请往后站
Sir, please stand back.
道格拉斯·卡特兰
Douglas Cartland.
几张镇外的发票
Some P.I. from out of town.
- 你发现了什么？- 孩子们发现了这件夹克
- What do you got there? - The boys found this jacket down there.
- 上面有血迹 - 直接拿到物证中心去
- There's blood on it. - Go hand it over to forensics,
看看上面是谁的血迹
just find out whose blood it is.
海瑟·曼森 莎伦·达·席尔瓦
Heather Mason, Sharon Da Silva.
- 这女孩吗？- 可能就是她
- This girl? - Maybe this is her.
找她并问下卡特兰的事
See what we got on this Cartland,
把监控带子调出来
pull the security tapes,
我要看看这儿今晚发生了什么
I want to see what happened here tonight.
嘿
Hey.
他们发现那死了个人 你看见了吗？
They found a guy dead in there, did you see it?
是…
Yeah, uhh…
怎么了？
What's wrong?
- 我不可以说出来 - 没事的 和我说说
- I can't tell you. - It's okay. You can tell me.
不行 我现在好混乱
No, I can't, because, I have no idea what's going on in my head now.
哈利的语音信箱：是我 请留言
Harry's voice on phone: It's me. Leave a message.
爸爸 你听到留言的话给我打电话
Dad, dad, call me when you get this, please.
天有点冷啊
Look, you're cold.
你的外套呢？
Where's your coat?
快披上
Come here.
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
你能看到吗？
Do you see them?
- 啊 谁啊 跑步那个？- 不是
- Yeah, who, the runner? - No.
没事 那看来我真的有点晕
Never mind. It's just another thing that prove that I'm going crazy.
那 你家在哪？
So, where's home?
在几街区以外
A couple of blocks away.
不 我问的是之前 你是从哪搬来的？
No, I mean before. Where did you come from?
没哪 真的 我和我爸爸一直都在换地方
Nowhere, really. I travel a lot with my dad.
你觉得梦境和现实之间有区别吗？
Do you think there is a difference between dreams and reality?
你怎么这么和人聊天啊？
What happened to the small-talk?
「你用Facebook吗」这些吗？
No "what's your favourite band", "do you Facebook", nothing like that?…
Facebook是个屁 你用那玩意？
Fuck Facebook. Do you?
我从没想过用那个
I never think about it.
- 大家都想着玩那个 - 我可没有
- Everybody thinks about it. - Not me.
我的生命也够坎坷的了
Look, my life is complicated enough.
你应该和我祖父聊聊 他总是想着这些
You should talk to my grandfather. That's all he ever thinks about.
他都着了魔了
It drove him crazy.
- 我也着了魔了 - 不 不 我是说他疯了
- It's driving me crazy. - No, No, I mean he is.
精神失常
Bat-shit nuts.
他回到了我那又小又甜蜜的家乡
Back in my sweet, little hometown,
利昂那多老头 就在他软垫病房里胡说八道
Old man Leonard drools in a padded cell.
他会告诉你从来就没有梦这东西 只有无尽的一层盖着一层的事实
He will tell you there are no such things as dreams, just endless realities all piled on top of each other.
有些人能看到怪物 而另一些人…看到的只是人
Some people see monsters, Other people just see… people.
- 他们为什么要把他关起来？- 是我妈妈指控他的
- And they locked him up for that? - My mother had him committed.
- 天 - 真的 她有点咄咄逼人 我妈妈
- Jesus. - Yeah, she's kind of intimidating, my mother.
幻想和现实之间并无界限
No difference between fantasy and reality.
- 我觉得我并不喜欢我的现实生活 - 你觉得谁会喜欢？
- I don't think I like my reality. - You think anyone does?
至少我是 那个我认同的自己 至于你…
At least I'm, who I think I am.
对 特别真实…
Yeah, pretty real…
…还有 挺漂亮的
… and just, pretty.
你搭讪的水平真烂
Oh, a lousy pick up line.
经常奏效么？
Does it often work?
以前没试过
I never tried it before.
效果不好吗？
How did it go down?
这可是搭讪的大忌
It was a crime against pick-up lines.
你挺有趣的 茜瑟
You're kind of funny, Heather.
你特别混乱 但是我不知道…
You're pretty fucked up, but I don't know, I …
我想你其实应该很傻很天真
I think you're goofy fun inside.
很傻很天…能这么评价我也挺好
Goofy fun… That would be nice for a change.
不说了 快到家了
Anyway, this is my street.
- 谢谢你送我回来 - 有机会了我还会再送你的
- Thanks for walking me back. - I'd like to do it again sometime.
文森特 你很好 但是…
Vincent, you're nice, but…
- 但我不觉得你想了解我 - 我想
- I don't think you wanna know me. - I do.
不 你不想
No, you don't.
我会再给你打电话的
I'm gonna call you later.
我可没给你号码
I didn't give you my number.
再见啦！
See you around!
爸爸？
Dad?
爸爸！
Dad!
「到寂静岭来」
"COME TO SILENT HILL"
爸爸！
Dad!
爸爸…
Dad…
爸爸！
Dad!
茜瑟 我是文森特 听见你在喊 没事吧？
Heather, it's Vincent. I heard you yell. Is everything alright?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
你看
Look,
那是血吗？
Is that blood?
- 你叫警察了吗？- 不能叫
- Did you call the police? - I can't.
- 为什么不叫？他们能帮助你 - 就是不能叫
- Why not? They can help. - I just can't!
- 行吗？- 行
- Okay? - Okay.
你知道寂静岭在哪吗？
Well, do you know where this Silent Hill is?
不 那是…
No, it's …
那是我梦见的地方 我爸爸 他… 他警告过我绝对不能到那去
It's something that I dreamt about. My dad, he… He warned me never to go there.
但是我认得那标记
But I know that symbol.
就是这个
This is it.
他把东西都收在这
He kept it all in here.
「莎伦」
"SHARON"
- 是你妈妈么？- 我的养母 露丝
- Is this your mom? - My adoptive mom, Rose.
你是被收养的？
You were adopted?
是的 我不知道我的亲生父母是谁
Yeah, I never knew my real parents.
- 这些都是你写的吗？- 对…
- Did you write all of these? - Yeah.
- 知道那是什么吗？- 不知道
- Do you know what that is? - No.
看起来好像这边还有一块能组合在一起
Looks like there's another side that fits in here.
枪？你为什么要拿枪？
A gun? Why do you need a gun?
- 曼森小姐 我们是警察 - 我还以为你没报警呢
- Miss Mason, it's the police. - I thought you said you didn't call.
- 我没有 - 那他们为什么在这？
- I didn't. - Then why are they here?
- 发生了什么 茜瑟？- 我得走了
- What is going on, Heather? - I have to go.
要是他们抓住我 我就再找不到我爸爸了
If they catch me, I'll never find my dad.
抓住你？为什么他们要抓你？
Catch you? Why would they catch you?
- 你干了什么？- 没什么！我什么也没干 我发誓
- What have you done? - Nothing! I didn't do anything, I swear.
- 帮帮我 - 你想让我怎么帮你？
- Help me. - What do you want me to do?
- 会开车吗？- 什么？
- Can you drive? - What?
我不会开车 你会吗？
I can't drive. Can you?
桑提尼 过来
Santini, come here.
你不是想找到充分的证据吗？
You want a probable cause?
看这个
This is it.
这里到底发生了什么？
What the hell happened here?
感觉是某个团伙组织的标志？
That look like a gang tag to you?
我觉得不是 但我从没见过这样的东西
But I've never seen anything like it.
给犯罪现场小组打电话 把他们叫来
Call Crime Scene, get them down here.
- 那女孩呢？- 她是凶杀嫌疑人
- What about the girl? - She's a murder suspect.
「我亲爱的莎伦
"My dearest Sharon,
你读这封信的时候说明我已经出事了
If you are reading this then something has happened to me.
你现在只能靠自己了
You're on your own now.
别试图找我了
Don't try to find me.
不管你去哪 都不要到寂静岭去
And whatever you do, don't go to Silent Hill.
我和你妈妈发誓要保证你的安全 但是我没做到
I promised your mother I'd keep you safe, but I failed.
我知道你觉得我们在躲避警察
I know you think we're running from the police,
因为我两年前在波特兰杀了人
because of the man I killed in Portland two years ago.
你不能永远保护她！
You can't protect her forever!
爸爸！
Dad!
但事实是…他不是简简单单的一个贼
But the truth is… He wasn't just a random thief.
收拾你的东西 我们走
Get your things, we're leaving.
他是被派来带你回寂静岭的
He was sent to take you back to Silent Hill.
他是教会的成员 那些人想要你 他们需要你
He was a member of the Order. These people want you, they need you.
我不知道原因 但是他们会用尽一切办法把你拖回去
I don't know why, but they will do everything in their power just to draw you back.
你必须反抗他们
You must resist it.
我试着保护你的安全
I tried to keep you safe.
但是从未故意向你撒谎 是不得不这么做
And I never meant to lie to you, but I had to.
你会在我的笔记本里找到真相 我发现的所有东西
You'll find the truth in my notebooks. As much as I could find out.
我希望你读了我所了解的东西之后 能知道你到底是谁
I hope that when you read what I learned, you can finally begin to understand who you really are.
原谅爸爸没有告诉你真相
Please forgive me for not telling you the truth.
但我是为了保护你才这样做
But I did it to protect you.
爱你 莎伦「
I love you, Sharon."
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
需要停一下吗？
Do you wanna stop?
不用
No.
书上说什么？
What does it say?
讲了很多
So much.
他画的我都看的懂 但这太疯狂了
I know his writing, but this is crazy.
上面说：「寂静岭最初是罪犯的殖民地
It says, "Silent Hill was originally a prison colony,
建在从印第安人手里抢来的土地上
built on ground taken from the native Indians.
他们称作寂静灵魂之地「
They called it, The Place of the Silent Spirits".
永远都别在古老的印第安墓地上盖房子
Never build on the ancient Indian burial grounds.
我觉得大家都知道
I thought everyone knew that.
这上面还说：「有个叫天佑会的种族狂热者
It says here, "Religious zealots called the Order of Valtiel,
最近的100年秘密地管理着镇子
secretly ran the town for the last 100 years.
他们在等待一个孩子的降生 她将成为神灵的容器
They were waiting for a child to be born to be a vessel for their god.
神将复活 重塑这个世界「
Who would then be resurrected and make the world anew."
听起来好像一个疯狂的末日邪教
It sounds like one of those crazy doomsday cults.
嗯 确实是
Yeah. Sounds like it.
还有一篇新闻文章
There is a newspaper article.
「煤矿火灾失控」
"Fire in the coal mines got out of control"
「整个地区都在燃烧 在地下深处 每个人都务必撤离」
"The whole place is still burning, deep underground. Everyone had to leave."
而我爸爸就是不相信那个
My dad doesn't believe that, though.
不信？
No?
他说那个地方是被妖童的力量所诅咒
He says the town was cursed by the power of a demon child.
她叫爱莉 教会想要用火净化她
Her name was Alessa. This Order tried to cleanse her with fire.
但是他们失败了 爱莉…
But they failed. And Alessa's revenge
召唤了黑暗世界 满是令人害怕的生灵
was to summon a world of darkness, filled with terrifying creatures.
这里说是她的「护卫和刽子手」
This one, it says, is her "guardian and executioner".
我们得停下了
We should stop.
- 不 我想继续走 - 我很累
- No, I want to keep going. - I'm tired.
我得休息 你也要休息
I need rest, you need rest.
你觉得他们会找到我们吗？
Do you think they'll find us?
最后肯定有人能找到
Someone will, eventually.
- 还有得走吗？- 不
- You think we're far? - No.
不 很接近那了
No, I think we're very close.
但我觉得你不该去…
And I don't think you should go…
- 什么？- 我觉得你爸爸是对的
- What? - I think your dad is right.
我觉得你不应该去寂静岭
I don't think you should go to Silent Hill.
我得去找他
I need to find him.
你也读了他的笔记了 他想让你逃跑
You read his notebooks. He wants you to run.
- 文森特… - 不 听我说 那个教会要找你
- Vincent… - No, listen to me. The Order, they want you.
我想这就是他们带走哈利的原因
I think that's why they took Harry.
- 让你回来 - 我没有选择
- To make you come back. - I don't have a choice.
- 你还不明白吗？- 我懂
- Don't you understand that? - I understand.
我只是…
I just…
我只是不想你出事
I just don't want anything to happen to you.
你没睡？
You didn't sleep?
没有
No.
我们不能再往前走了
We can't go any further.
我们已经说过这个了 我得去
We already talked about this. I have to.
- 为什么你就是不相信我？- 是为了我爸爸 你不会懂的
- Why can't you just trust me? - It's for my dad. You don't understand.
- 我明白 - 不 你不懂
- I do. - No, you don't.
你怎么会懂？
How could you?
因为我就是教会的孩子
Because I am a child of the Order.
什么？
What?
我在寂静岭出生长大
I was born and raised in Silent Hill.
我被选择降生在这世界就是为了确保你的回归
I was chosen to come into this world, to make sure you return.
不会的
No.
不 怎么可能
No, that's not possible.
教会被困在寂静岭了 笔记上都说了
The Order are trapped in Silent Hill. The notebook says so.
少数人饶幸逃出来
It is possible for a few to escape just for a while,
但需历经苦难
but it requires, it requires sacrifice, and suffering.
你是被选中的人！
You have been chosen for this!
- 你怎么能这样对我？- 我这一生都被灌输
- How could you do this to me? - My whole life all I've been taught,
我们每一个人都被灌输 爱莉是这世界的大恶魔
All that any of us have taught is that Alessa is the great evil of the world.
她困住我们 她带来黑暗
She trapped us, she brings the darkness.
还有你…你是这罪恶的一部分
And you… you are part of that evil.
但是我 我知道这不是真的
But I, I know that's not true.
在看到你之后 在和你度过这段时间之后 我知道你并不邪恶 我…
After seeing you, after spending this time with you, I know you're not evil, I …
要是你是爱莉的一部分的话…
If you are part of Alessa…
…你就是纯洁的那部分
…you're the innocent part.
- 一直以来你都在撒谎 - 我必须这么做
- Every step of the way, you lied. - I had to.
他们一直在盯着 保护他们在这世界上的灵魂 你看见过他们
They were watching, protecting their spirits into the world. You saw them.
是你把我爸爸带走的
You took my dad.
相信我 那与我无关
Please believe me, I had nothing to do with that,
- 对不起 - 为什么要带走他 为什么不带走我？
- I'm sorry. - Why take him, why not just take me?
你得心甘情愿回去才行
Because you have to return of your own free will.
带走他 他们知道你就会跟着去的
Taking him, they knew you'd follow.
我怎么会这么重要？
Why do I matter so much?
因为爱莉不消失 教会没法获得自由
Because the Order can't be free until Alessa is gone.
她的力量把教会困住 再次变成完全体之前她是打不败的
Her power keeps them trapped, and she can't be destroyed until she's whole again.
- 有了你才有可能 - 那我父亲呢？
- You will make that happen. - What about my dad?
- 他还活着吗？- 活着 但是活不长了
- Is he still alive? - Yes, but not for long.
我母亲克劳迪娅 她一旦达到目的 就立刻让他死
My mother, Claudia, won't keep him alive after she has what she wants.
- 他在哪？- 在镇地下的圣殿里
- Where is he? - In the sanctuary beneath the town.
- 等等 茜瑟 别去… - 不行！
- Wait, Heather, stop… - No!
你需要这个
You need this.
你得找到另一半 只有这个方法才能救你父亲
You have to find the other half. It's the only way you'll be able to save your dad.
那一半在我祖父那
My grandfather has it.
精神病院的那个？
The one in the asylum?
对 里昂那多·沃尔夫
Yes, Leonard Wolf.
- 太危险了 让我帮你吧 - 不！离我远点！
- It's dangerous. Let me help you. - No! Get off of me!
- 听我说！- 不…
- Listen! - No…
- 怎么回事？- 黑暗力量来了
- What is happening? - The Darkness is coming.
茜瑟…
Heather…
怎么回事？
What's going on?
停下！让它停下！
Stop! Make it stop!
- 是你干的 - 不
- You did this. - No.
不是我
It's not me.
我怎么能做到？
How could it be me?
因为你是爱莉的一部分
Because you are part of Alessa.
你太靠近了 你的力量使黑暗力量穿越了结界的
You're so close, you allowed the darkness to break through.
文森特 到底怎么回事？
Vincent, what is going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
文森特！
Vincent!
欢迎来到寂静岭
WELCOME TO SILENT HILL
烧死女巫！
Burn the Witch!
你不应该来这
You should not be here.
他们会利用你的
They will use you.
现在我们都会受尽折磨的
We will all suffer now.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你是他的母亲
You're her mother.
爱莉的母亲
Alessa's mother.
你怎么能让他们烧死她？
How could you let them burn her?
不 我爱她
No, I loved her.
没事的 小宝贝
It's alright, sweetheart.
没事的 没关系的
It's okay. It's alright
我被欺骗了
I was deceived.
我从未想过让她受这样的痛苦
I never wanted this for her.
爱莉：你要把我带到哪去？
Alessa: Where are you taking me?
妈妈！妈妈！
Mommy! Mommy!
爱莉是特别的
Alessa was special.
她是唯一一个能逃过火刑的孩子 这就是她被选中的原因
She was the only one who could survive the fire, that's why she was chosen.
不 不！
No, no!
但这只是给予了我们诅咒
But it only led to our damnation.
你们是自作自受
You all got what you deserved.
对 我变成了恶魔的母亲
Yes, and I became the mother of the demon.
但是你是她的女儿
But you are her daughter.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
爱莉没有在火中丧生 但是她却承受了极大的痛苦
Alessa didn't die in the fire, but she suffered so much.
那痛苦带来的只有愤怒
For pain was only matched by the rage.
因为那愤怒 她的力量在增加…
And with that rage, her powers grew…
…超出了她的控制
… beyond all comprehension.
爱莉知道自己内心仍存部分仁慈
Alessa knew there was a part of her, that could still be free from pain.
所以她就把她最后的 纯洁的那部分灵魂
So she took that last, innocent part of her soul
安放在一个新生的孤儿身上
and placed it into a new born, orphan child.
就是你
You.
你被秘密的带离这里
You were secretly taken from here,
被一对不知情的 有爱心的夫妇抚养长大
to be raised by loving, but unaware parents.
你是爱莉唯一能感觉到爱的一部分
You're the only part of Alessa that feels love.
你能够平息怨恨 你不应该回来
You have the balance of hate. You should never have come back.
现在你的到来
Because now you have given the order what they could never have…
岂不是成全教会消灭爱莉和你
A way to destroy Alessa. And you.
我父亲在哪？
Where is my father?
除非牺牲你自己 否则无法救回你父亲
There is nothing you can do to save him without damning yourself.
我不在乎 告诉我你知道什么
I don't care. Just tell me what you know.
我知道黑暗力量要来了
I know the darkness is coming.
现在外面很危险
It's safer to be inside.
快跑
Run.
跑啊！
Run!
不！
No!
什么？
What?
帮帮我
Help me.
不！
No!
快跑
Run.
我来了 我来帮你！
I'm here, I'll help you!
- 怎么回事？- 快跑 她来了
- What happened? - Run, she's coming.
什么来了？
What's coming?
快点！快跑！
Come on! Run!
- 你是从哪来的？- 我走错路…
- Where did you come from? - I took a wrong turn…
在雾里迷了路…
Got lost in the fog…
走！快点！
Go! Come on!
不！
No!
这边
This way.
快跑！
Run!
走！
Go!
我唯一的儿子…
My own son…
母亲 求你了…
Mother, please…
…背叛了我们
… betrayed us.
她不是恶魔
She is not evil.
你的意志被她的黑暗侵蚀了
Your mind is corrupted by her darkness.
将这项任务交予你这样的没经验的人
You were young to be given this task…
我明白
I understand.
是你创造了爱莉
You created Alessa.
黑暗力量是将你的邪恶报应到我们身上
The darkness is your evil reflected back at us.
- 她是无辜的 - 她是无辜的？
- She is innocent. - She is innocent?
- 你疯了 像你祖父一样你疯了 - 杀了他！烧死他！
- You are insane, just as your grandfather is insane. - Kill him! Burn him!
折磨他！
Make him suffer!
- 让神来审判他！- 不！
- Let the God judge him! - No!
你成功了
You succeeded.
虽然你疯了 但是你还是把她引回来了
Even in your madness, you guided her back to us.
换作我妹妹蕙莎 就做不到
What my sister, Christabella, could not achieve, I shall.
你很快会得到救助
Salvation is at hand.
- 你不会一直疯下去 - 不
- And a broken mind can be mended. - No.
母亲 求你别
Mother, please don't.
把他带到精神病院去
Take him to the asylum.
- 不 - 给他治疗治疗
- No. - Cure him.
不！
No!
「溪港精神病院」
"Brookhaven Asylum"
里昂那多
Leonard.
<i>你觉得还有别人知道吗？</i>
Do you think someone knows?
<i>没有</i>
No.
<i>没人知道</i>
No one knows.
<i>好的</i>
Okay.
<i>我也爱你</i>
I love you too.
里昂那多·沃尔夫
Leonard Wolf.
好的
Okay.
S-12
S-12.
里昂那多
Leonard.
你好 孩子
Hello, child.
过来 过来点 让我能摸到你
Please come, come closer, so, so I could touch you.
我不想这样做
I don't think so.
- 是克劳迪娅送你来的吗？- 克劳迪娅？
- Did Claudia send you? - Claudia?
- 对 - 不 是把你扔到这了
- Yeah. - No. She put you here.
我女儿竟说我被黑暗力量侵蚀了
My own daughter says that I'm corrupted by the darkness.
她说我是怪物
She says that I'm a monster.
可她比我可严重多了
She's far worse than I am.
她也被黑暗力量吞噬了
She is also corrupted by the same darkness.
- 我在找我的父亲 - 他失踪了？
- I am looking for my father. - Is he lost?
他在寂静岭
He's in Silent Hill.
有好多寂静岭 你确定是我们这的？
There are many Silent Hills. Are you sure it's this one?
文森特说你知道怎样…
Vincent said you know how to…
文森特 那个小叛徒…
Vincent, that little traitor…
我的亲人背叛了我！
My own flesh and blood turned against me!
听听 啊
Listen. Ahh.
你可能能听到他被折磨的哭喊吧
You may be able to hear the cries of his torment.
他在这？
He's here?
要修复你的意志还有别的地方吗？
Where else would you go to mend your mind?
像你这样？
Like yours is?
怎么了…
Why …
我是…一项进行中的项目
I'm just… an ongoing project.
我有一半这个
I have half of this.
- 你能帮帮我吗？- 听着…
- Will it help me? - Listen…
我瞎了 孩子
I'm blind, child.
我看不到你那拿的是什么
I cannot see what you have there.
请放到我手上 我会试试帮你的
Place it in my hand and I will try to help you.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
来吧
Come on.
- 你知道这是什么 - 我是教会的主教
- You know what it is. - I was the Master of the Order.
我怎么会不知道梅特鲁纹章？
How could I not know the Seal of Metatron?
她从我这偷走 并带那个孩子逃走
It was stolen from me and used by her to escape with the child.
没有了它我们没法召唤神灵
Without it we cannot summon the god.
它是把钥匙 那它能打开什么？
It is a key. What does it unlock?
事物的本质
The true nature of things.
我要找到另一半
I need to find the other half.
但你已经找到了 另一半就是我！
But you've already found it. The other half is in me!
你在干什么？不要
What are you doing? No!
不要！
Stop!
现在…我看到你的真面目了
Now… I see the truth of you.
你是恶魔！必须毁灭你！
You're a demon! You must be destroyed!
今天不行
Not today.
两半合起来了
Two halves coming together.
完整了
It's complete.
爱莉？
Alessa?
你能感觉到我吗？
Can you feel me?
你知道我在这 对吗？
You know I'm here, don't you?
你知道我拿到了梅特鲁纹章
You know I've got the Seal of Metatron.
谁来帮帮我
Somebody help me.
不
No.
后退！后退！
Get back! Get back!
还有你！
And you!
后退！
Get back!
- 小心！- 后退！
- Look out! - Get back!
照做！照做！
Do it! Do it!
我怎么才能找到我爸爸？
How can I find my dad?
- 茜瑟 帮帮我 - 告诉我他在哪？
- Heather, help me. - Tell me where he is.
在湖边公园下面的圣殿
In the sanctuary, beneath the amusement park.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
好的
Fine.
快！
Hurry!
我快着呢！
I am hurrying!
不 该死
Oh, shit.
等下！
Stop!
- 茜瑟 等下 - 我们需要把刀
- Heather, stop. - We need a knife.
你怎么生活在这样的地方？
How can you live like this?
和黑暗力量 这些怪物生活在一起？
This darkness, those creatures?
我的世界就是这样子啦
That's all I've ever known.
黑暗力量现在应该衰落了
Darkness should have faded by now.
- 为什么这样说？- 你离爱莉这么近
- Why hasn't it? - You're so close to Alessa,
两部分再次融合 就会改变世界
two halves coming together again, it's changing the world.
那会发生什么？
What's gonna happen?
这得看你
That's up to you.
湖边公园就在那边
Lakeside Amusement Park is over there.
那就是圣殿的入口了
And the entrance to the sanctuary.
你觉得你能救他吗？
Do you think you can save him?
我得试试 我爸爸不顾性命保护我
I have to try. My dad gave up his life to protect me.
- 我觉得他更希望你别来这里 - 你怎么会知道
- I think he'd want you to leave. - You don't know that.
如果他爱你的话 他不会想让你涉身险境的
If he loved you, he wouldn't want you to be in any danger.
要是你爱着某人 你知道你永远都不会放弃的
And if you love someone, you know that you will never give up.
不 等等！
No, wait!
蹲下
Get down.
- 看 - 是守卫吗？
- Look. - Are they soldiers?
不完全是
Not really.
我们把他们叫做「兄弟会」 教会最虔诚的教徒
We call them "the Brethren". The most devout servants of the Order.
看到他们的面具了吗？他们呼吸不到黑暗的空气
See the masks? They won't breathe the air of the darkness.
他们觉得那会侵蚀他们
They think it corrupts them.
我希望你能找到他
I hope you find him.
我希望能自由快乐的生活 这是我最憧憬的
I hope live free and happy, It's more than I ever did.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
文森特 不！
Vincent, no!
- 爱莉？- 女儿
- Alessa? - Daughter.
妹妹
Sister.
- 我自己 - 不
- Self. - No.
我给了你生命 你才活得如我所愿
I gave you life so you could live my dream.
你是我不受痛苦束缚的部分
You're the part of me that can be free of this pain.
活着 感受爱
Live, and feel love.
你什么都感觉不到吗？
Do you feel nothing?
只能感觉到恨
Nothing but hate.
他们说你是恶魔
They say you are a demon.
- 他们说的对 - 是你创造了这噩梦
- They are right. - You created this nightmare.
寂静岭的每个人都有不同的噩梦
Everyone has a different nightmare in Silent Hill.
- 我就是噩梦的源头 - 我要救我的爸爸
- I am theirs. - I have to save my father.
他不是我爸爸 也不是你的
He's not my father, or yours.
祭品 必须得有
And sacrifices, have to be made.
去死！
Go to hell!
事到如今 你还不明白吗？
Don't you see? We're already here.
可不由得你
And you're not welcome!
你是不是觉得 我不会毁了你？
Do you think, I won't destroy you?
我不在乎
I don't care.
我就是你
I am you.
是时候取回我给你的一切了！
Time to take back what I gave you!
停下！
Stop!
我们是一体 茜瑟
We are one, Heather.
爸爸！
Dad!
莎伦！
Sharon!
莎伦
Sharon.
你别伤害她！
You don't hurt her!
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
看看你周围
Look around you.
这是我们的圣殿
This was our sanctuary.
远离黑暗力量的最后安全之地
A last, safe place from the darkness.
可现在 即使在这 也陷入了她的罪恶之中
And now, even here, has fallen to her evil.
但是感谢神灵 你最后还是到达了这里
But praise the god, that you are here, finally.
- 你解救了我们 - 我没为你们做任何事
- You have delivered us. - I have done nothing for you.
你完成了一切
You have done everything.
打败了阿丽萨 合并了纹章
Defeated Alyssa. Re-joined the seal.
你是救世主
You are the savior.
如果我做了这么多事
If I've done so much,
那就把我父亲放了
Then let my father go.
他不能走 他的血将滋养新生的神灵…
He cannot go. His blood will feed the newborn god …
而神灵将从你的身体里重生
Just as your body will be its incubator.
为什么？
Why?
- 为什么是我？- 那就是你的命运
- Why me? - It is your destiny.
许多年前你就被选为容器
You have been chosen many years ago to be the vessel.
神灵只能从你的血肉中重生
The god can only be born through your flesh.
那样我们就能从这牢狱中自由
And then we will be free from this prison
清洗这世上的罪恶
to cleanse the world of its sins.
我们需要…你的身体
And all we need… is your body.
不！
No!
你放她走！
You leave her alone!
你已经拿到了梅特鲁纹章 有了它我就能召唤神灵
You have the Seal of Metatron. With it, I can summon the god.
把它给我
Give it to me.
拿着吧 我想看看你到底是什么
Take it, I want to see the truth of what you are.
- 爸爸！- 莎伦
- Dad! - Sharon.
看灰烬…
The ash…
已经不再下了！
It's stopped!
- 是你做的吗？- 不 不是我
- Was it you? - No, it's not me.
我想从现在开始这的一切就会不一样了…
I think things are gonna be different around here from now on…
教会的力量已经不存在了 爱莉的噩梦结束了
The Order's power is broken. Alessa's nightmare is over.
- 她死了 - 会有第二个爱莉的
- She's gone. - Another one will come.
这就是迷失灵魂的归宿
This is the place of lost souls.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
- 我不能走 - 为什么？
- I can't leave. - Why?
- 我得留在这 - 但是爸爸 我们已经自由了
- I have to stay here. - But dad, we're free.
我们安全了
We're safe.
- 第一次获得了自由 - 我得去找你的妈妈
- For the first time. - I'm gonna find your mother.
你救了我的命 我无所回报
You saved my life. And I can never repay you.
但是露丝还陷在某处
But Rose is still trapped here somewhere.
- 我得去找她 - 我来帮你找吧
- I'm gonna find her. - Let me help you find her.
不 我答应过你妈妈 一旦你安全了 我就会回去的
No. I promised her, once you
这是我的任务 你已经完成了你该做的
This is my task. You've done what you had to do.
现在 我想你获得完全的自由
Now, I want you to be free, finally.
你明白我为什么要这么做吗？
Do you understand why I have to do this?
你是爸爸最疼爱的女儿
You're everything I could've ever wished for.
- 我爱你 宝贝 - 我也爱你 爸爸
- I love you, baby. - I love you too, Dad.
文森特 照顾好我的女儿 知道了吗？
Vincent, look after my little girl, do you hear?
我不觉得她需要我照顾
I don't think she needs me for that.
走吧
Come on.
好
Yeah.
进来吧
Come on in.
小心脚下
Watch your step.
- 谢谢 - 不用谢
- Thanks. - No problem.
能遇到我是你们的运气 我很长时间没走这条路了
You're lucky I came by. I haven't been this way in a long time.
- 特拉维斯·格雷迪 - 文森特
- Travis Grady. - Vincent.
- 莎伦 - 很高兴见到你
- Sharon. - Nice to meet you.
你们这对小恋人要到哪去？
So where're you two lovebirds headed?
带我们离开这越远越好
Just take us as far away from here as you can.
- 没错！- 懂了
- Amen to that! - Got it.
（阁下正离开寂静岭）
（欢迎来到寂静岭）